Comix Collection 2001.0084
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Comix Collection
undated, 1968-1996
2001.0084
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
5.0 Linear feet
70+ titles.
Various.
Scope and Content
The collection contains incomplete runs of over 70 underground comix titles. Materials are acquired irregularly and have been integrated into the Alternative Press Collection.
Acquisition Information
The materials have been donated or purchased individually.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to alternative and underground press publications. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Comic books, strips, etc.; Underground comics.
- Series I: Collection, undated, 1968-1984
  - Adventures of the Little Green Dinosaur, Berkeley, Calif., Last Gasp. #1
    General note
    APC File
  - Air Pirates; funnies, San Francisco, CA. #1, (1972)
  - Apex Treasury of Underground Comics, New York: Links Books, 1974
    Dodd Call No. C3098
  - Armageddon, Berkeley, Calif.: Last Gasp Eco Comics, Inc. #1-3
  - Baloney Moccasins Comics, New York #1
  - Bicentennial Grossouts, s.l.: [Biggy Eagle Enterprises] #1 (only one published)
  - Big Ass Comics, San Francisco, Calif., Rip Off Press. #1-2
  - Bijou Funnies, Chicago, Ill., #2,5
  - Binky Brown meets the Holy Virgin Mary, Berkeley, Last Gasp Eco-Funnies, 1972
    Dodd Call No. WNC 3
  - Chicanos, New York: North American Congress on Latin America, 1973
    Dodd Call No. WE 71
  - Class War Comix, Sussex, England: Epic Productions, #1
    Periodicals
  - Collected Adventures of the Fabulous Furry Freak Brothers, San Francisco, CA, Rip Off Press, 1971
    Dodd Call No. WNC 1
  - Comic Buyer's Guide, Krause Publications, Inc. Iola, WI. #1181, 1996
    Storage note
  - Conspiracy Capers, Chicago, Ill., #1
  - Cultural Correspondence, Providence, RI, 1-9, 12-14
  - Da'kota, Millenium Publications, Narragansett, RI. #2, 1996
  - Dan O'Neill's Comics and Stories, San Francisco, Calif., v. 1 #1-3, v. 2 #1-2
  - Despair, Berkeley, Calif., Print Mint, #1
  - Dopin' Dan, Berkeley, Calif., Last Gasp Eco-Funnies, v. 1 #1-3
  - Dr. Atomic, Berkeley, Calif.: Last Gasp Eco-Funnies, Inc., #1-3
  - Einstein Monster, San Francisco, Calif., San Francisco Comic Book Co., #2
  - Fantagor, Berkeley, Calif., Last Gasp Eco-Funnies, #1-2
  - Far Out West, San Francisco, Calif.: Performing Arts Social Society, Inc., #1
  - Feds 'n' Heads, Austin, Texas, #1
  - First Kingdom, Berkeley, Calif.: Comics and Comix Co., #1, (1974)
  - Gay Hearthrobs, San Francisco, Calif.: Fulhorne Publications, #1
  - Gen of Hiroshima, San Francisco: Educomics, #1, (1980)
  - Girl Fight Comics, Berkeley, Calif.: The Print Mint, #1-2
  - Give Me Liberty, San Francisco, Rip Off Press, 1976
    APC Pam 190
  - Gothic Blimp Works, Ltd., New York, 2-3, 5-6, 8
    APC Folio
  - Heavy Comix, San Francisco, CA, 1972
    Dodd Call No. WNC 4
  - Home Grown Funnies, Milwaukee, WI, Krupp Comic Works, Jan. 1971
  - How to Read Donald Duck: imperialist ideology in the Disney Comic, 1975
    Dodd Call No. XA I.6 no.74
  - Incredible Shrinking American Dream; an illustrated peoples history of the United States, Boston: Alyson Publications, 1981
    APC BK f55
  - Inner City Romance, Berkeley, Calif., Last Gasp Eco-Funnies, #1-2
  - It Ain't Me Babe Comix: Women's Liberation, Berkeley, Last Gasp Eco-Funnies, 1970
    Dodd Call No. WHQ 15
  - Kid's Liberation Coloring Book, San Francisco, Last Gasp Eco-Funnies, 1971
    Dodd Call No. C2122
  - Laugh in the Dark, Berkeley, Calif., Last Gasp Eco-Funnies, #1
  - Legion of Charlies, Berkeley, Calif., Last Gasp Eco-Funnies, 1971
    Dodd Call No. WNC 2
  - Mad, New York, N. Y., Educational Comics, Vol. 1 no. 3
  - Merton of the Movement, Berkeley, Calif., Last Gasp Eco-Funnies, #1
  - Mom's Homemade Comics, Milwaukee, Wisc., Kitchen Sink Enterprises, v. 1 # 1-3
  - Motor City Comics, Detroit, Mich., R. Crumb Productions, #1-2
  - Mr. Natural, San Francisco, Calif., San Francisco Comic Book Co. #1-2
  - Octobriana and the Russian Underground, New York, Harper & Row, 1971
    Dodd Call No. C2124
  - Outlaw Comix, Lehigh Valley, Pa., #1
  - Perfecto Comics, Berkeley, Calif.: Print Mint, 1973
    APC Pam 193
  - R. Crumb's Comics and Stories, Los Angeles, CA, Rip Off Press, #1
    APC Pam 1115
  - R. Crumb's Fritz the Cat, New York: Ballantine Books, 1969
    APC BK f27
  - R. Crumb's Head Comix, New York: Ballantine Books, 1968
    APC BK f26
  - Rip Off Review of Western Culture, San Francisco, CA, Rip Off Press, 1972 June - July
  - San Francisco Comic Book, San Francisco, Calif., San Francisco Comic Book Co., v. 1 # 2-3
  - SFU Komix, Burnaby, B. C., Canada, #1
  - Sine Massacre, Paris, Imprimerie Graphoprint, #5-7
  - Skull Comics, Berkeley, Calif., Last Gasp Eco-Funnies, #2-3
  - Slow Death, Berkeley, Calif., Last Gasp, #1-3, 5-6
  - Smile, Milwaukee, Kitchen Sink Enterprises, v. 1, #1, 1970 Summer
  - Snarf, Milwaukee, WI, Kitchen Sink Enterprises, v. 1, #2-3, 5-6
  - Subject Index to Comic Books and Related Material, East Lansing: Special Collections, Michigan State University Libraries, 1975
    Dodd Call No. XA I.6 no.72
  - Tales from the Sphinx, Milwaukee, WI, Kitchen Sink Enterprises, v. 1, #1 or 2, 1972 November
  - Tasty Comix, Washington, D. C. #2
  - Teenage Trash, Chicago, Ill.: Adam's Apple Distributing Company, #1
  - Tin-Pot Foreign General and the Old Woman, London, England: Hamish Hamilton, 1984
    APC BK f67
  - Tortoise and the Hare, Berkeley, Calif., Last Gasp Eco-Funnies, #1
  - Trashman, Berkeley, CA, Fat City, #1
  - Uneeda Comix, Berkeley, Calif., Print Mint, #1
  - Vamperotica, Brainstorm Comics, Fayetteville, NC. #19, 1996
  - Verotika, Verotik, Los Angeles, CA. #11., 1996
  - Wiley Willy's Illuminations, Berkeley, Calif.: Print Mint, 1971
    APC Pam 232
  - Wimmen's Comix, Berkeley, Calif.: Last Gasp Eco-Funnies, Inc. #1-6
  - XYZ Comics, Milwaukee, WI: Krupp Comic Books, 1972
    APC Pam 233
  - Yellow Dog, Berkeley, Calif., Print Mint, #1-5, 7-8, 13-14, 17-22
    APc File
  - Young Lust, San Francisco, Calif., #1-2, 4
  - Your Hytone Comics, San Francisco, Calif. Apex Novelties, #1
  - Zap Comix, San Francisco, Calif., #0-3, 5